Inventory of the Ted Dalton Papers 1933-1978, 1952-1959
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Ted Dalton Papers, 1933-1978, 1952-1959.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 81 D17
14 boxes.
Correspondence, speeches, news clippings, photographs, recordings, reels of film, chiefly 1952-1959, of Ted Dalton (1901-1989). Virginia state senator, 1944-1959; Republican candidate for governor of Virginia, 1953, 1957; and appointed as U. S. district judge of the Western District of Virginia, 1959.
J. Lindsay(James Lindsay) Almond,; Howard Baker,; Ezra Taft Benson,; Harry Flood Byrd,; Ted Dalton,; Colgate W.(Colgate Whitehead) Darden,; Dwight D.(Dwight David) Eisenhower,; Gerald R. Ford,; Mills E.(Mills Edwin) Godwin,; A. Linwood(Abner Linwood)Holton,; A.E. Dick Howard,; Richard M.(Richard Milhous) Nixon,; Davis Young Paschall,; Richard H.(Richard Harding) Poff,; Lewis F. Powell,; Nelson A.(Nelson Aldrich) Rockefeller,; Thomas B.(Thomas Bahnson) Stanley.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 6 cartons, 5/25/1981.
Gift: 4 boxes, 1/11/1982.
Gift: 50 items, 4/26/1982.
Biographical/Historical Information
Theodore Roosevelt Dalton was born 3 July 1901 in Carroll County, Virginia, the son of Currell and Lodoska Maritn Dalton. he received his B.A. from the College of William and Mary as well as his law degree. Dalton was Commonwealth's Attorney for Radford, Virginia and state senator from 1944-1960. He was the Republican Party candidate for governor in 1953 and 1957. Dalton was appointed federal judge for the Western District of Virginia. His adopted son was John N. Dalton who served as governor of Virginia. Ted Dalton died 30 October 1989.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1933-1978, of Ted Dalton, Virginia state senator, 1944-1959; Republican candidate for governor of Virginia in 1953 and 1957; and U.S. District judge for the Western district of Virginia. Includes correspondence, speeches, news clippings, photographs, recordings, reels of film and legal opinions.
Subjects covered include Republican Party politics, the Virginia General Assembly, highways,compulsory automobile insurance, segregation, the Gray Commission Report (Commission on Public Education), the College of William and Mary, and Dalton's appointment as federal judge.
Prominent correspondents include J. Lindsay Almond, Howard Baker, Ezra T. Benson, Harry F. Byrd, Sr., Harry F. Byrd, Jr., John N. Dalton, Colgate W. Darden, Dwight D. Eisenhower,Gerald R. Ford, Mills E. Godwin, Albertis S. Harrison, A. Linwood Holton, J. Edgar Hoover, A. E. Dick Howard, Richard Nixon, Davis Y. Paschall, Richard H. Poff, Lewis F. Powell, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas B. Stanley, A. E. S. Stephens, William M. Tuck, and Edward E. Willey.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Each of the boxes in the collection is arranged chronologically by date. Each box or group of boxes included in one series is divided into four basic subseries,
1. Correspondence,
2. Speeches,
3. News Clippings,
4. Other Papers.
Organization
This collection is arranged into 11 Series:
1. Papers,
2. Papers,
3. Gubernatorial Papers,
4. Papers,
5. Papers,
6. Papers,
7. Papers,
8. Papers,
9. Federal Judgeship,
10. Papers,
11. Photographs, Videotape, Etc.
Index Terms
Persons:
Almond, J. Lindsay(James Lindsay), 1898-1986.; Baker, Howard.; Benson, Ezra Taft.; Byrd, Harry Flood, 1887- 1966.; Byrd, Harry Flood, 1914-; Virginia. Governor(1978-1982:Dalton); Darden, Colgate W.(Colgate Whitehead), 1897-1981.; Eisenhower, Dwight D.(Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-; Godwin, Mills E.(Mills Edwin), 1914-; Holton, A. Linwood(Abner Linwood), 1923-; Howard, A.E. Dick.; Nixon, Richard M .(Richard Milhous), 1913-; Paschall, Davis Young, 1911-; Poff, Richard H.(Richard Harding), 1923-; Powell, Lewis F., 1907-; Rockefeller, Nelson A.(Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Stanley, Thomas B.(Thomas Bahnson), 1890-1970.
Subjects:
College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ).; Roads-- Virginia.; Insurance, Automobile--Virginia.; Segregation in education--Virginia.; Patronage, Political--United States.
Components List
  Series 1: Miscellaneous Papers
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1933-1967. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1959. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence with T. X. Parsons, 1941. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Correspondence: Republican Primary: with Frank McWane, and Earl Lutz, 1949. (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Correspondence, 1953. (Box-folder 1:22)
      Correspondents include Dwight D. Eisenhower, Richard M. Nixon, Harry F. Byrd.
    - Congratulatory Letters, 1953. (Box-folder 1:24)
      Includes Tennessee Governor Frank Clement, and Dick Davis.
    - Correspondence, January 2-February 12, 1954. (Box-folder 1:25)
      Correspondents include Walter S. Newman, and Richard H. Poff.
    - Correspondence with Graham Claytor, February 13-17 1954. (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Correspondence with Governor Thomas Stanley, Judge Johnpaul, and Harold Stassen, 1956. (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 1:32)
    - Correspondence, 1963. (Box-folder 1:34)
      Includes President Eisenhower's Inaugural Prayer.
  - Speech, 1943. (Box-folder 1:9)
    Speech by Judge Hopkins.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1933-1959. (Box 1)
    - News Clippings, 1933. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - News Clippings: Ted Dalton elected head of Bar Association, 1942. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - News Clippings, 1944. (Box-folder 1:10)
    - News Clippings, 1944. (Box-folder 1:11)
    - News Clippings, 1945. (Box-folder 1:12)
    - News Clippings, 1946. (Box-folder 1:13)
    - News Clippings, 1947. (Box-folder 1:14)
    - News Clippings, 1948. (Box-folder 1:15)
    - News Clippings, 1951. (Box-folder 1:18)
    - News Clippings, 1951. (Box-folder 1:19)
    - News Clippings - National Campaign, 1952. (Box-folder 1:20)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 1:21)
    - News Clippings - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1953. (Box-folder 1:23)
    - News clippings - General Assembly, 1958. (Box-folder 1:29)
    - News Clippings - Doings at the State Capitol, 1958. (Box-folder 1:30)
    - News Clippings, 1967. (Box-folder 1:35)
  - Other Papers, 1933-1959. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Papers. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Invitation to President Eisenhower's birthday party. Congressional Record, clipping announcing Ted Dalton's honorary LL.D. from William and Mary.
    - Extra Copies of campaign speeches, and related news clippings, 1952, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Personal items such as thank you notes and postcards, 1954, 1957, 1958. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Undated Papers, n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Including photos, news clippings, and legal opinions.
    - State Senate Bills, 1944. (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Virginia State Senate Bills, 1950. (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Legislative Papers, 1956. (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Report of the President of William and Mary, 1958. (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Republican Gubernatorial Candidate, 1961. (Box-folder 1:33)
  Series 2: Papers
- Papers, 1952. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1952. (Box-folder 2:1)
    Correspondents include A. S. Harrison, Jr., and Theodore R. McKeldin.
  - Speeches: Gubernatorial Nomination, 1952. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - News Clippings, 1952. (Box-folder 2:4-12)
    - News Clippings: Presidential Campaign, 1952. (Box-folder 2:3)
    - News Clippings: State and National Campaigns, 1952. (Box-folder 2:4)
    - News Clippings: State and National Campaigns, 1952. (Box-folder 2:5)
    - News Clippings, 1952. (Box-folder 2:6)
    - News Clippings: Republican National Convention, 1952. (Box-folder 2:7)
    - News Clippings, 1952. (Box-folder 2:8)
    - News Clippings: Republican National Convention, 1952. (Box-folder 2:9)
    - News Clippings: Republican National Convention, 1952. (Box-folder 2:10)
    - News Clippings, February 1952. (Box-folder 2:11)
    - News Clippings: National Republican Campaign, April-November 1952. (Box-folder 2:12)
  Series 3: Gubernatorial Papers
- Gubernatorial Papers, 1953-1957. (Box 3-5)
  - Correspondence, 1953. (Box 3-5)
    - Correspondence: Agricultural Drought Relief, 1953. (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Correspondence: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:2)
      Correspondents include Edward E. Willey, Thomas B. Stanley.
    - Correspondence: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Correspondence: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:4)
      Correspondents include Richard H. Poff, Harry F. Byrd.
    - Correspondence: Campaign for Governor, April-October 1953. (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Correspondence: Campaign for governor, November-December 1953. (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Correspondence: Campaigns: correspondents include Lewis F. Powell, 1953. (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Correspondence, July-December 1953. (Box-folder 5:2)
      Correspondents include J. Lindsay Almond.
    - Correspondence: Industrial Development, and Campaign, July-October 1953. (Box-folder 5:4)
      Correspondents include Ezra T. Benson.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Congratulatory Letters, 1953. (Box-folder 5:7)
      Correspondents include A. Linwood Holton.
  - Speeches, 1953. (Box 3-5)
    - Speeches: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Speeches: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:14)
      Includes nomination acceptance speech.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:15)
      Re: mentally ill, Two-Party System, tuberculosis.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1953. (Box-folder 5:20)
  - News Clippings, 1953. (Box 3-4)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 3:8)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 3:9)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 3:10)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:11)
    - News Clippings, November 4-17 1953. (Box-folder 3:12)
    - News Clippings; Drought in Virginia, 1953. (Box-folder 3:13)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 3:14)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 3:15)
    - News Clippings: Education, 1953. (Box-folder 3:16)
    - News Clippings, October 1953. (Box-folder 3:17)
    - News Clippings, September 23-30 1953. (Box-folder 3:18)
    - News Clippings, September 2-October 25 1953. (Box-folder 3:19)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 3:20)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor - Highway Plan, 1953. (Box-folder 4:3)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:4)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:5)
    - News Clippings: Vote fraud, 1953. (Box-folder 4:6)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:7)
    - News Clippings, 1953. (Box-folder 4:8)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:9)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor - Health Care, 1953. (Box-folder 4:10)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, September 2-October 25 1953. (Box-folder 4:11)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, September 1-19 1953. (Box-folder 4:12)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:13)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:14)
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:15)
      Re: Thomas Stanley.
    - News Clippings: Campaign for Governor, 1953. (Box-folder 4:16)
  - Other Gubernatorial Papers, 1953. (Box 4-5)
    - Education in Virginia, 1953. (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Education in Virginia, 1953. (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Education in Virginia, July-September 1953. (Box-folder 5:5)
      Includes news clippings.
    - General Assembly Legislation, 1953-1954. (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1953. (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Literature, 1953. (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Literature, 1953. (Box-folder 5:11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Virginia Highways, 1953. (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Virginia Highways, 1953. (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Campaign Briefs, 1953. (Box-folder 5:16)
      Re: highways and convict labor.
    - Source Materials on Health Care, 1953-1954. (Box-folder 5:17)
  Series 4: Papers
- Papers, 1954. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1954. (Box-folder 6:1-7)
    - Correspondence, February 1954. (Box-folder 6:1)
      Correspondents include Clifton A. Woodrum, Jr.
    - Correspondence. (Box-folder 6:2)
      Correspondents include Richard Poff.
    - Correspondence, April-December 1954. (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Correspondence, 1954. (Box-folder 6:4)
      Re: State Senate and Labor Law.
    - Correspondence, January-July 1954. (Box-folder 6:5)
    - Correspondence, March 1954. (Box-folder 6:6)
    - Correspondence, March 1954. (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Speeches, 1954. (Box 6)
    - Speeches, 1954. (Box-folder 6:10)
    - Speeches: National Election, 1954. (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Speeches: General Assembly, 1954. (Box-folder 6:14)
  - News Clippings, 1954. (Box 6)
    - News Clippings, 1954. (Box-folder 6:13)
    - News Clippings: Highways, 1954. (Box-folder 6:15)
    - News Clippings, 1954. (Box-folder 6:16)
    - News Clippings: General Assembly, 1954. (Box-folder 6:17)
    - News Clippings: Dalton's doings at the Capitol, 1954. (Box-folder 6:18)
    - News Clippings: General Assembly, 1954. (Box-folder 6:19)
    - News Clippings, 1954. (Box-folder 6:20)
  - Other Materials, 1954. (Box-folder 6)
    - Materials relating to the General Assembly, 1954. (Box-folder 6:8)
    - Materials relating to Compulsory Automobile Insurance, 1954. (Box-folder 6:9)
    - Republican National Campaign Relation, 1954. (Box-folder 6:12)
  Series 5: Papers
- Papers, 1946-1960. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1960. (Box-folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Republican National Finance Committee, 1955. (Box-folder 7:9)
      Correspondents include Lewis F. Powell, Jr.
    - Correspondence: Republican National Finance Committee, 1955. (Box-folder 7:10)
    - Correspondence (congratulatory letters): Segregation of Public Schools, 1955. (Box-folder 7:11)
      Correspondents include Gov. Thomas Stanley.
    - Correspondence: State Senate, 1955. (Box-folder 7:12)
      Correspondents include Mamie Eisenhower.
    - Correspondence: Gray Commission Report, integration of schools, 1955. (Box-folder 7:16)
      Correspondents include Lewis F. Powell, Jr. and Gov. Thomas Stanley.
    - Correspondence with President Eisenhower, 1955. (Box-folder 7:17)
      Includes acceptance speech for GOP nomination at state senator.
    - Correspondence: Gray Commission Report, November-December 1955. (Box-folder 7:19)
  - Speeches, 1946-1960. (Box-folder 7)
    - Speech: School Integration; news clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:1)
    - Speeches: Highways, 1955. (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Speeches: School integration, 1955. (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Speeches, 1955. (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Speeches, 1955. (Box-folder 7:7)
    - Speeches and Correspondence: Public Education. (Box-folder 7:18)
  - News Clippings, 1955-1956. (Box-folder 7)
    - News Clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:13)
    - News Clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:14)
    - News Clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:15)
      Includes Gray Commission Report.
    - News Clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:20)
    - News Clippings, 1955. (Box-folder 7:21)
    - News Clippings, 1956. (Box-folder 7:22)
    - News Clippings, 1955-1956. (Box-folder 7:23)
  - Other Papers, 1946-1960. (Box 7)
    - Acts of General Assembly, extra session, 1955. (Box-folder 7:2)
    - State Campaign, 1955. (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Publications, 1946-1960. (Box-folder 7:8)
  Series 6: Papers
- Papers, 1955-1957. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1956. (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1956. (Box-folder 8:2)
      Re: Integration.
    - Correspondence and Speeches, 1956. (Box-folder 8:2a)
    - Correspondence, 1956. (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Correspondence, 1956. (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Correspondence: Republican National Convention, 1956. (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Speeches, 1955-1957. (Box 7)
    - Speeches, 1956. (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Speeches, 1956. (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Speeches, Correspondence, and News Clippings, 1956. (Box-folder 8:14)
      Re: Presidential Election Campaign.
  - News Clippings, 1955-1957. (Box 7)
    - News Clippings, 1956, n.d. (Box-folder 8:11)
    - News Clippings, 1956. (Box-folder 8:12)
    - News Clippings, 1956. (Box-folder 8:15)
      Re: Segregation, National Republican Convention, Republican Campaign in Virginia.
    - News Clippings, July-December 1956. (Box-folder 8:16)
    - News Clippings, 1956. (Box-folder 8:17)
    - News Clippings, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 8:18)
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1956. (Box-folder 8:19)
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Election, 1956. (Box-folder 8:20)
  - Other Papers, 1955-1957. (Box 8)
    - Republican National Committee, 1956. (Box-folder 8:1)
    - General Assembly: Uninsured Motorists, 1956. (Box-folder 8:6)
    - National Election, 1956. (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign: Driver's Education, 1956. (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Virginia Senate Bills, 1956. (Box-folder 8:10)
    - General Assembly, 1956. (Box-folder 8:21)
  Series 7: Gubernatorial Papers
- Gubernatorial Campaign Papers, 1956-1957 (Box 9-10)
  - Correspondence, 1957. (Box 9-10)
    - Correspondence and Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Correspondence, 1957. (Box-folder 9:5)
      Re: Segregation.
    - Correspondence, January-December 1957. (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Speeches, 1957. (Box 9-10)
    - Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:5)
    - Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:6)
    - Speeches, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 10:7)
      Re: Gubernatorial Campaign, Integration.
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:8)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:10)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:11)
    - Speeches: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 10:12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:13)
      Re: Education, Integration, Highways.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches: Integration, 1957. (Box-folder 10:14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches: Integration, 1957. (Box-folder 10:16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:17)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, July-December 1957. (Box-folder 10:18)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches 1957. (Box-folder 10:19)
    - Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:20)
      Re: Gubernatorial Campaign and special session of General Assembly.
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:21)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Speeches, 1957. (Box-folder 10:22)
  - News Clippings, 1957. (Box 9)
    - News Clippings: Integration and Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign News Clippings, 1957. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Re: Teacher's pay and integration.
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Campaign. 1957. (Box-folder 9:9)
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Campaign. 1957. (Box-folder 9:10)
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Campaign. 1957. (Box-folder 10a)
    - News Clippings, 1957. (Box-folder 9:11)
      Includes General Assembly (1956).
    - News Clippings: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 9:12)
    - News Clippings, 1957. (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Other Papers, 1957. (Box 9-10)
    - Sen. Dalton's taped acceptance speech; overall length 5 minutes., 1957., film reel. (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Segregation Related Papers, 1957. (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1957. (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign Literature, 1957. (Box-folder 10:4)
  Series 8: Papers
- Papers, 1957-1960. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1960. (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, January-April 1957. (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Correspondence: Judgeship, etc., November-December 1959. (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 11:8)
      Correspondents include Howard Baker, J. Lindsay Almond.
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 11:9)
      Re: the College of William and Mary.
  - Speeches, 1958-1959. (Box 11)
    - Speeches, 1958. (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Speeches, 1959. (Box-folder 11:15)
      Includes induction speech as a U.S. Judge.
  - News Clippings, 1958-1960. (Box 11)
    - News Clippings, 1958. (Box-folder 11:3)
    - News Clippings, 1959-1960. (Box-folder 11:10)
    - News Clippings, 1959. (Box-folder 11:11)
    - News Clippings: General Assembly, 1959. (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Other Papers, 1958-1959. (Box 11)
    - General Assembly and Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 11:5)
    - General Assembly, 1959. (Box-folder 11:6)
    - General Assembly, 1959. (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Education in Virginia, 1958. (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Manual of General Assembly, 1958. (Box-folder 11:14)
  Series 9: Federal Judgeship
- Federal Judgeship, 1958-1960. (Box 12-13)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1960. (Box 12-13)
    - Correspondence, May 1958 (Box-folder 12:1)
      Re: Federal Judgeship.
    - Correspondence, June 1958. (Box-folder 12:2)
      Re: Federal Judgeship
    - Correspondence, July-December 1958. (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Correspondence, 1958. (Box-folder 12:4)
      Re: General Assembly.
    - Correspondence, 1958. (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:9)
      Re: Federal Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters.
    - Congratulatory letters, 1959. (Box-folder 12:10)
      Re: Judgeship.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:11)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:12)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:13)
      Re: Federal Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters; correspondents include William M. Tuck and A. E. S. Stevens.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:14)
      Re: Federal Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters; correspondents include Lewis F. Powell, Jr.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:15)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:16)
      Re: Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters; correspondents include Alvin C. Chandler.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:17)
      Re: Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:19)
      Re: Judgeship: Congratulatory Letters; correspondents include Lewis F. Powell, Jr. Colgate W. Darden, and William H. Tuck.
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:20)
    - Correspondence, August 1959. (Box-folder 12:21)
    - Correspondence, 1959. (Box-folder 12:24)
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 12:26)
      Includes Judge Barksdale, Judge Bryan, and Howard Baker.
    - Correspondence, Nov. 1959 - Aug. 1960. (Box-folder 13:2)
      Correspondents include Alvin D. Chandler.
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Correspondence, 1960. (Box-folder 13:5)
      Correspondents include Alvin D. Chandler and Richard Poff.
    - Correspondence, 1961. (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Correspondence, 1961. (Box-folder 13:8)
      Includes Richard L. Poff and Davis Y. Paschall.
    - Correspondence, Jan. - June 1962. (Box-folder 13:10)
    - Correspondence, July - Dec. 1962. (Box-folder 13:11)
    - Correspondence, Jan. - July 1963. (Box-folder 13:15)
    - Correspondence, July - Dec. 1963. (Box-folder 13:16)
    - Correspondence, Jan. - June 1964. (Box-folder 13:17)
      Correspondents include Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Correspondence, June - Dec. 1964. (Box-folder 13:18)